Inventory of the A. Piatt Andrew papers
Hoover Institution Archives
A. Piatt Andrew papers
1832-1950
2006C26
Andrew, A. Piatt (Abram Piatt)
49 manuscript boxes, 11 oversize boxes (33.4 linear feet linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The A. Piatt Andrew papers provide a record of the life and work of a prominent American who achieved distinction in a number of fields in the first part of the 20th century. Andrew taught economics at Harvard before being appointed to government office, first as Director of the United States Mint and then as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury. Leaving the Treasury Department, he then acted on his own initiative as the founder and director of the American Field Service, a volunteer ambulance corps that operated with the French army on the battlefields of Europe during World War I. Following service in the United States Army, Andrew was elected to Congress in 1921 and remained a representative from Massachusetts until his death in 1936. All phases of his career in public service are documented in the papers.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1873 Born, La Porte, Indiana
1893 Bachelor of Arts, Princeton College
1900 Doctor of Philosophy, Harvard University
1900-1909 Instructor and assistant professor of economics, Harvard University
1909-1910 Director, United States Mint
1910-1912 Assistant Secretary of the U.S. Treasury
1914-1917 Organizes and directs the American Field Service, a volunteer ambulance corps serving in France
1917 Commissioned as major, United States Army
1917 Awarded the Légion d'Honneur and Croix de Guerre by the French government
1918 Promoted to lieutenant colonel, United States Army
1921-1936 Member, United States House of Representatives
1936 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The A. Piatt Andrew papers provide a record of the life and work of a prominent American who achieved distinction in a number of fields in the first part of the 20th century. Andrew taught economics at Harvard before being appointed to government office, first as Director of the United States Mint and then as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury. Leaving the Treasury Department, he then acted on his own initiative as the founder and director of the American Field Service, a volunteer ambulance corps that operated with the French army on the battlefields of Europe during World War I. Following service in the United States Army, Andrew was elected to Congress in 1921 and remained a representative from Massachusetts until his death in 1936. All phases of his career in public service are documented in the papers.
The Correspondence series in the papers reflects the wide compass of Andrew's professional and personal relationships. There are exchanges of letters with important political figures-among these, Henry Cabot Lodge, Calvin Coolidge, William Howard Taft, Woodrow Wilson, and Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt-as well as academics such as the philosopher William James and the economist Frank William Taussig. There is extensive correspondence with Boston socialite and art collector Isabella Stuart Gardner, and with Andrew's friend and fellow American Field Service volunteer, Henry Davis Sleeper. The series also includes a large quantity of correspondence with members of Andrew's family, including his sister, Helen Andrew Patch, and parents, Abram P. and Helen M. Andrew. These span the time from Andrew's early years as a student in private schools until his later career as a politician, and provide insight into family life and education in this period. They also chart the social progress of a banker's son from Indiana who became part of New England's cultural and political establishment.
The Speeches and Writings series contains a considerable number of articles and addresses concerning banking and currency issues, as well as many speeches made during the course of his political career. These include numerous campaign speeches, often to Republican audiences, and many talks to veterans at American Legion meetings and Memorial Day gatherings.
For the most part, the remainder of the collection is organized chronologically, according to the various stages of Andrew's public career. The Treasury Department file series is comprised of materials pertaining to Andrew's service as Director of the United States Mint and as Assistant Secretary of the Treasury. The Political campaign file series contains correspondence and other documents relating to Andrew's first, unsuccessful campaign for Congress. The American Field Service file series contains correspondence and other documents relating to Andrew's time as head of the volunteer ambulance corps in France. It also includes materials from the American Field Service's postwar activities in providing scholarships for American and French students.
The large Congressional file series has an extensive amount of routine correspondence, organized chronologically, as well as a subject file encompassing Andrew's major legislative concerns during his time in Congress. These include the issue of Allied war debts after World War I, especially as they pertained to France, whose debt burden Andrew, a confirmed Francophile, sought to ease, and Prohibition, whose repeal was a goal that Andrew endorsed. The fishing industry, of great importance to Andrew's constituents, and immigration are other topics covered in the subject file.
Additionally, the papers contain separate materials pertaining to the Andrew family without reference to A. Piatt Andrew. The Andrew family materials series includes correspondence relating to A. Piatt Andrew's grandfather, Abram Piatt Andrew, Jr., and his father, Abram Piatt Andrew III. There is also correspondence relating to his sister, Helen Andrew Patch, as well as documents pertaining to her involvement in civil defense efforts during World War II and her activities on behalf of the Wendell Willkie presidential campaign in 1940.
There are a large number of scrapbooks in the Oversize materials series. These contain clippings that detail Andrew's experiences in the Treasury Department, his time in France with the American Field Service, and his subsequent Congressional career.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
American Field Service.; United States. Congress. House.; United States. Dept. of the Treasury.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Finance, Public--United States.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; World War, 1914-1918--Medical care.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.; Massachusetts--Politics and government--1865-1950.
Collection Contents
- Biographical file, 1884-1936 (Box 1-2)
  Contains album, article, brochure, campaign literature, clippings, diaries, drawing, membership cards, memorial addresses, obituaries, programs, report cards, residency permit, transcript of interview, and will
  Arranged by physical form
  - Album relating to tour of Europe, 1891 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical article, brochure, and sketch, 1921-1935 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Brochure commemorating award of Légion d'Honneur to Andrew, 1917 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Campaign literature, 1928 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Clippings, 1909-1935
    - 1909-1924 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1925 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1926 (Folder 1: 7)
    - 1927 (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1928-1929 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1930 (Folder 1: 10-11)
    - 1931-1932 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1933-1934 (Folder 1: 13)
    - 1935 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Diaries, 1894-1913
    - 1894-1896 (Folder 1: 15)
    - 1897-1899 (Folder 1: 16)
    - 1900-1902 (Folder 1: 17)
    - 1903 (Folder 1: 18)
    - 1907 (Folder 1: 19)
    - 1909-1910 (Folder 1: 20)
    - 1911-1913 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Drawing, 1885 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Membership cards and certificates, 1898-1930 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Memorial addresses and tributes, 1936 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Obituaries, 1936 (Folder 2: 5-6)
  - Programs, 1884-1935 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Report cards, 1886 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Residency permit, 1916 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Transcript of interview, 1934 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Will, 1932 (Folder 2: 11)
- Correspondence, 1885-1936 (Box 2-17)
  Contains letters, postcards, and enclosures
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Letters of congratulation on being awarded the Légion d'Honneur, 1917 (Folder 2: 12)
  - General, 1895-1935
    - A, 1912-1927 (Folder 2: 13)
    - B, 1895-1935 (Folder 2: 14)
    - C, 1898-1935 (Folder 2: 15)
    - D, 1897-1930 (Folder 2: 16)
    - E, 1905-1931 (Folder 2: 17)
    - F, 1896-1929 (Folder 2: 18)
    - G, 1902-1933 (Folder 3: 1)
    - H, 1902-1934 (Folder 3: 2)
    - I-J, 1907-1930 (Folder 3: 3)
    - K, 1905-1935 (Folder 3: 4)
    - L, 1907-1932 (Folder 3: 5)
    - M, 1895-1935 (Folder 3: 6)
    - N-O, 1903-1926 (Folder 3: 7)
    - P-Q, 1898-1931 (Folder 3: 8)
    - R, 1902-1933 (Folder 3: 9)
    - S, 1906-1933 (Folder 3: 10)
    - T, 1921 (Folder 3: 11)
    - W, 1896-1935 (Folder 3: 12)
    - Y-Z, 1905-1929 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Unidentified, 1890-1933 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Adams, Charles F., 1912-1932 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Aertsen, Guillaem, 1904 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Aldrich, Nelson W., 1912 (Folder 3: 17)
  - American Legion (Lemuel Bolles, James F. Carens, James D. Drain, H. A. Folsom, Hanford MacNider, John R. McQuigg, Alvin Owsley, John R. Quinn, Frank W. Snow, Edward E. Spafford), 1920-1928 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Anderson, Carl, 1913 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Andrew family, 1886-1898
    Compilation of letters sent by Andrew to his parents, sister, and grandmother
    - 1886 (Folder 4: 1-2)
    - 1888-1890 (Folder 4: 3)
    - 1891-1892 (Folder 4: 4)
    - 1893 (Folder 4: 5)
    - 1894 (Folder 4: 6)
    - 1895 (Folder 4: 7-8)
    - 1896 (Folder 4: 9)
    - 1897 (Folder 4: 10)
    - 1898 (Folder 4: 11-12)
  - Andrew, Abram P. and Helen M. (parents), 1886-1932
    - 1886 (Folder 5: 1-2)
    - 1887 (Folder 5: 3-4)
    - 1888 (Folder 5: 5)
    - 1889 (Folder 5: 6)
    - 1890 (Folder 5: 7)
    - 1891 (Folder 5: 8-9)
    - 1892 (Folder 6: 1-2)
    - 1893 (Folder 6: 3-4)
    - 1894 (Folder 6: 5-9)
    - 1895 (Folder 7: 1-3)
    - 1896 (Folder 7: 4-7)
    - 1897 (Folder 7: 8-10)
    - 1898 (Folder 8: 1-3)
    - 1900-1914 (Folder 8: 4)
    - 1915-1916 (Folder 8: 5)
    - 1917 (Folder 8: 6)
    - 1918-1920 (Folder 8: 7)
    - 1921-1932 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Andrew, Catherine Piatt, 1924 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Atherton, Ray, 1910 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Bacon, Gaspar Griswold, 1910 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Bacon, Robert Low, 1910-1922 (Folder 8: 12)
  - Baldensferger, Fernand, 1919-1920 (Folder 8: 13)
  - Balfour, Oswald, 1922 (Folder 8: 14)
  - Balme, L., 1899-1902 (Folder 8: 15)
  - Bartlett, Mary Gordon, 1894-1896 (Folder 8: 16)
  - Beal, Thomas P., 1908-1913 (Folder 8: 17)
  - Beck, James M., 1925-1931 (Folder 8: 18)
  - Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1912 (Folder 8: 19)
  - Beston, Henry, 1923 (Folder 8: 20)
  - Beveridge, Albert J., 1920-1924 (Folder 8: 21)
  - Bigelow, William DeFord, 1923-1935 (Folder 8: 22)
  - Bingham, William J., 1919-1926 (Folder 8: 23)
  - Bird, Charles S., 1914 (Folder 8: 24)
  - Bliss, Robert Woods, 1919-1936 (Folder 8: 25)
  - Boardman, Alice L., 1896-1897 (Folder 8: 26)
  - Boardman, William D., 1896 (Folder 8: 27)
  - Bosis, Lauro and Lillian de, 1926 (Folder 9: 1)
  - Bradley, Leverett, 1903 (Folder 9: 2)
  - Brigham, William E., 1912 (Folder 9: 3)
  - Brown, Harriet J., 1896 (Folder 9: 4)
  - Bryan, William Jennings, 1914 (Folder 9: 5)
  - Bulkley, Roy J., 1913 (Folder 9: 6)
  - Burton, Theodore E., 1911-1926 (Folder 9: 7)
  - Capper, Arthur, 1923-1930 (Folder 9: 8)
  - Carens, Thomas, 1929-1932 (Folder 9: 9)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1914 (Folder 9: 10)
  - Carnegie Hero Fund Commission (F. M. Wilmot), 1914 (Folder 9: 11)
  - Carter, James C., 1896-1897 (Folder 9: 12)
  - Cartier, Emile and Marie de, 1925-1932 (Folder 9: 13)
  - Century Magazine (R. W. Gilder), 1909 (Folder 9: 14)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America, 1913 (Folder 9: 15)
  - Chapman, John Jay, 1919-1921 (Folder 9: 16)
  - Chess, Lura, 1894 (Folder 9: 17)
  - Chew, Oswald, 1926-1927 (Folder 9: 18)
  - Choate, Robert B, 1922-1930 (Folder 9: 19)
  - Christie, Francis A., 1892-1893 (Folder 9: 20)
  - Clark, Frank Emmons, 1914 (Folder 9: 21)
  - Claudel, Paul, 1928 (Folder 9: 22)
  - Clémenceau, Georges, 1922 (Folder 9: 23)
  - Clévenot, Elisabeth, 1927-1928 (Folder 9: 24)
  - Cobb, Henry Ives, Jr., 1904 (Folder 9: 25)
  - Cochran, Samuel, 1897-1921 (Folder 9: 26)
  - Comfort, William Wistar, 1899-1901 (Folder 9: 27)
  - Condon, R. E., 1922 (Folder 9: 28)
  - Connor, William D., 1933 (Folder 9: 29)
  - Consalus, Helen Fitch, 1935 (Folder 9: 30)
  - Cooke, Thornton, 1913-1931 (Folder 9: 31)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1920-1923 (Folder 9: 32)
  - Coolidge, L. A., 1922 (Folder 9: 33)
  - Corm, Sophie, 1894-1895 (Folder 9: 34)
  - Cox, Channing H., 1921-1923 (Folder 9: 35)
  - Crissey, Forrest, 1933 (Folder 9: 36)
  - Curley, James M., 1930 (Folder 9: 37)
  - Daeschner, Emile, 1925 (Folder 9: 38)
  - Darwin, L., 1908 (Folder 9: 39)
  - Davis, Livingston, 1900 (Folder 9: 40)
  - Davison, H. P. and Kate, 1909-1916 (Folder 9: 41)
  - Denby, Edwin and Marion, 1922-1924 (Folder 9: 42)
  - Derby, Richard, 1903 (Folder 9: 43)
  - Dessez, Léon, 1930 (Folder 9: 44)
  - Dodd, Catherine I., 1898 (Folder 10: 1)
  - Donald, Malcolm, 1900 (Folder 10: 2)
  - Douglas, L. W., 1931 (Folder 10: 3)
  - Doumenc, Joseph, 1917-1922 (Folder 10: 4)
  - Drouin, R., 1921-1931 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Eastman, Ralph M., 1931-1932 (Folder 10: 6)
  - Eaton, Charles C., 1928 (Folder 10: 7)
  - Edwards, C. R., 1926-1929 (Folder 10: 8)
  - Eliot, Charles William, 1909-1922 (Folder 10: 9)
  - Emmet, Rosina H., 1896 (Folder 10: 10)
  - Farrell, Margaret Brady, 1923 (Folder 10: 11)
  - Fédération des Vétérans Français de la Grande Guerre, 1920 (Folder 10: 12)
  - Fèvre, Lilinie, 1899 (Folder 10: 13)
  - Fisher, Irving, 1914 (Folder 10: 14)
  - Fiske, Ethel, 1900 (Folder 10: 15)
  - Fleming, Owen, 1898-1931 (Folder 10: 16)
  - Forbes, Allan, 1912-1922 (Folder 10: 17)
  - Forgan, James B., 1912-1913 (Folder 10: 18)
  - Forness, Arthur A., 1927 (Folder 10: 19)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, 1921-1932 (Folder 10: 20)
  - Frew, Walter E., 1913 (Folder 10: 21)
  - Fuller, Alvan T. and Viola D., 1922-1933 (Folder 10: 22)
  - Fullerton, Morton, 1927-1928 (Folder 10: 23)
  - Galatti, Stephen, 1935 (Folder 10: 24)
  - Gardner, A. P., 1912-1914 (Folder 10: 25)
  - Gardner, Isabella Stuart, 1900-1925
    - 1900-1906 (Folder 10: 26)
    - 1907-1909 (Folder 10: 27)
    - 1911-1925 (Folder 10: 28)
  - Gibbons, Herbert Adams, 1927 (Folder 10: 29)
  - Goodwin, Elliot H., 1896-1898 (Folder 10: 30)
  - Gould, Carl F., 1900 (Folder 10: 31)
  - Gouraud, Henri, 1927-1933 (Folder 10: 32)
  - Grant, Alexander, 1900 (Folder 11: 1)
  - Grant, Robert, Jr., 1910 (Folder 11: 2)
  - Greene, Henry C., 1907 (Folder 11: 3)
  - Guild, Curtis, 1913 (Folder 11: 4)
  - Hale, Edward E., 1902 (Folder 11: 5)
  - Hall, Richard Henry, 1900 (Folder 11: 6)
  - Hallowell, John W., 1906 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Hamlen, Joseph R., 1930-1931 (Folder 11: 8)
  - Hammond, John Hays, Jr., 1920-1935 (Folder 11: 9)
  - Hancock, Walker, 1927-1935 (Folder 11: 10)
  - Hannigan, Judson, 1929-1930 (Folder 11: 11)
  - Hard, William and Anne, 1924-1930 (Folder 11: 12)
  - Hardon, Frances, 1931 (Folder 11: 13)
  - Haslehurst, Mary Alice, 1895-1896 (Folder 11: 14)
  - Henry-Haye, Gaston, 1927-1931 (Folder 11: 15)
  - Henry, Jules, 1925-1930 (Folder 11: 16)
  - Hepburn, M., 1909-1910 (Folder 11: 17)
  - Hibben, John Grier, 1913-1932 (Folder 11: 18)
  - Higginson, Henry L., 1907-1916 (Folder 11: 19)
  - Hooper, Alice Forbes Perkins, 1927-1932 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1926-1928 (Folder 11: 21)
  - Howell, Felicie Waldo, 1921 (Folder 11: 22)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1921-1923 (Folder 11: 23)
  - Huidekoper, Rosalind, 1910 (Folder 11: 24)
  - Huntington, Archer M. and Helen, 1910-1920 (Folder 11: 25)
  - Hurley, Patrick J., 1929 (Folder 11: 26)
  - Hyde, James H., 1905-1920 (Folder 11: 27)
  - Ingalls, David S., 1930-1932 (Folder 11: 28)
  - Ingersoll, Ernest, 1935 (Folder 11: 29)
  - Jackson, Russell Leigh, 1930-1935 (Folder 11: 30)
  - James, Elsie, 1910 (Folder 11: 31)
  - James, William and Alice H., 1902-1910 (Folder 11: 32)
  - James, William, Jr., 1906 (Folder 11: 33)
  - Jay, Delancey Kane, 1900 (Folder 11: 34)
  - Joffre, Joseph, 1926 (Folder 11: 35)
  - Johnston, Burton C., 1930-1931 (Folder 11: 36)
  - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1914-1926 (Folder 11: 37)
  - Kahn, Otto H., 1925 (Folder 11: 38)
  - Keller, Helen, 1928 (Folder 11: 39)
  - Kelley, Joseph W., 1929-1930 (Folder 11: 40)
  - Kellogg, Daniel F., 1913 (Folder 11: 41)
  - Kissam, Ethel, 1897 (Folder 11: 42)
  - Knowles, Leslie Appleton, 1904 (Folder 11: 43)
  - Knox, John B., 1913-1922 (Folder 11: 44)
  - Labouchère, P. de, 1924 (Folder 12: 1)
  - Lansing, Robert, 1914 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Larrieu, Henry, 1927 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Le Braz, Anatole, 1906-1919 (Folder 12: 4)
  - Lee, Thomas Amory, 1935 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Lee, Walter J., 1910 (Folder 12: 6)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1912-1924 (Folder 12: 7)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1930-1935 (Folder 12: 8)
  - Logan, W. Turner, 1924-1925 (Folder 12: 9)
  - Lopp, G. Washington, 1928 (Folder 12: 10)
  - Lufkin, W. W., 1919-1921 (Folder 12: 11)
  - Mabbett, Jack, 1907-1909 (Folder 12: 12)
  - Mabbett, May, 1907 (Folder 12: 13)
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1926 (Folder 12: 14)
  - MacNider, Hanford, 1921-1934 (Folder 12: 15)
  - Macrae, Robert, 1933-1934 (Folder 12: 16)
  - Mallet, Richard, 1918-1926 (Folder 12: 17)
  - Malone, Dudley Field, 1913-1914 (Folder 12: 18)
  - Manufacturers Record (Richard H. Emonds), 1925-1926 (Folder 12: 19)
  - Marcoux, Vanni and Madeleine, 1923-1928 (Folder 12: 20)
  - Marean, Edith Endicott, 1896 (Folder 12: 21)
  - Marvin, Florence Bianca, 1900 (Folder 12: 22)
  - Masury, Evelyn L., 1922-1930 (Folder 12: 23)
  - McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1913-1925 (Folder 12: 24)
  - McCormick, Muriel, 1925 (Folder 12: 25)
  - McMorran, Henry, 1913 (Folder 12: 26)
  - McMullin, John, 1925 (Folder 12: 27)
  - Means, Constance Gardner, 1925 (Folder 12: 28)
  - Mercer, Henry, 1911-1912 (Folder 12: 29)
  - Meyer, Alice, 1912-1914 (Folder 12: 30)
  - Montgomery, 1891-1894 (Folder 12: 31)
  - Montravel, Comte de, 1927 (Folder 12: 32)
  - Morawetz, Marjorie, 1932-1934 (Folder 12: 33)
  - Morier, A., 1926-1927 (Folder 12: 34)
  - Morrow, Dwight W., 1930-1931 (Folder 12: 35)
  - Münsterberg, Hugo, 1905-1907 (Folder 12: 36)
  - Newcomb, M. B., 1927 (Folder 13: 1)
  - Nichols, Jeannette P., 1925-1926 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Norton, Charles D., 1909-1910 (Folder 13: 3)
  - Noyes, A. W., 1913 (Folder 13: 4)
  - O'Brien, Robert L., 1913-1914 (Folder 13: 5)
  - O'Connell, William Cardinal, 1920-1929 (Folder 13: 6)
  - O'Neil, Gilbert W., 1935 (Folder 13: 7)
  - The Open Road, Inc., 1931 (Folder 13: 8)
  - Oulahan, Richard, 1928-1931 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Owen, Robert L., 1913 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Palgrave, R. H. Inglis, 1907-1908 (Folder 13: 11)
  - Parks, Betty L., 1907 (Folder 13: 12)
  - Pasey, Robert, 1933 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Passaga, Fénélon F. G. (Folder 13: 14)
  - Patch, Helen Andrew, 1885-1936
    - 1885-1894 (Folder 13: 15)
    - 1895-1899 (Folder 13: 16)
    - 1900-1925 (Folder 13: 17)
    - 1926-1930 (Folder 13: 18)
    - 1931-1936 (Folder 13: 19)
  - Patch, Isaac, 1925-1933 (Folder 13: 20)
  - Patrick, John, 1904 (Folder 13: 21)
  - Peabody, Federick W., 1926-1929 (Folder 13: 22)
  - Pershing, John J., 1923-1926 (Folder 14: 1)
  - Phillips, William, 1909-1914 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Pier, Roy, 1903 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Platt, Edmund, 1913 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Plehn, Carl C., 1913 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Pollard, F. Wilder, 1920 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Popoff, Constantine, 1925 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Powers, L. M., 1914 (Folder 14: 8)
  - Prince, Claire Morton, 1904 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Princeton Alumni Association (David W. Tibbott), 1933 (Folder 14: 10)
  - Puaux, René, 1897-1923 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Purdy, W. Frank, 1921 (Folder 14: 12)
  - Putliz, Wolfgang Gans, Edler Herr zu, 1921-1922 (Folder 14: 13)
  - Randall-MacIver, Joanna, 1914 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Recchia, Richard H., 1927 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Rhodes, James Ford, 1900-1921 (Folder 14: 16)
  - Robson, Eleanor, 1900 (Folder 14: 17)
  - Rogers, Edith Nourse, 1922-1925 (Folder 14: 18)
  - Roosevelt, Emily, 1934 (Folder 14: 19)
  - Roosevelt, Ethel Carow, 1910 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1913 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1920 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1911-1915 (Folder 14: 23)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr., 1921-1924 (Folder 14: 24)
  - Rosendahl, C. E., 1933 (Folder 14: 25)
  - Ross, Denman Waldo, 1902-1903 (Folder 14: 26)
  - Roussel, F., 1919 (Folder 14: 27)
  - Roz, Firmin, 1920 (Folder 14: 28)
  - Rust, Edgar C., 1905 (Folder 14: 29)
  - Sayons, André E., 1903 (Folder 14: 30)
  - Schafer, Sara Andrew, 1910 (Folder 14: 31)
  - Seligman, Edwin R. A., 1912-1927 (Folder 14: 32)
  - Seymour, John D., 1929-1932 (Folder 14: 33)
  - Siegfried, André, 1898-1926 (Folder 14: 34)
  - Siegfried, Ernest, 1911 (Folder 14: 35)
  - Siegfried, Jules, 1925-1927 (Folder 14: 36)
  - Simmons, B. T., 1910 (Folder 14: 37)
  - Sinkler, Caroline, 1922-1936 (Folder 14: 38)
  - Sleeper, Henry Davis, 1906-1929
    - 1906-1907 (Folder 15: 1)
    - 1908 (Folder 15: 2)
    - 1909-1910 (Folder 15: 3)
    - 1911-1929 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Smoot, Reed, 1912-1913 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Spencer, Charles E., 1933 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Speyer, Edgar, 1908-1912 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Stcherbinine, Michel, 1928 (Folder 15: 8)
  - Storey, Frank, 1906 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1910-1914 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Tardieu, André, 1927-1929 (Folder 15: 11)
  - Tarkington, Booth, 1923 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Taussig, Frank William, 1896-1919 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Thacher, John H., 1930 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Thébaud, Jean, 1926-1928 (Folder 15: 15)
  - Théodor, L. H., 1923-1927 (Folder 15: 16)
  - Thomas, Clara, 1905 (Folder 15: 17)
  - Thomas, Linda, 1900 (Folder 15: 18)
  - Thompson, W., 1912 (Folder 15: 19)
  - Tilden, William Morris, 1910 (Folder 15: 20)
  - Toy, Nancy, 1916-1927 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Tuckerman, John, 1915 (Folder 15: 22)
  - Tunney, Gene and Polly, 1931-1932 (Folder 15: 23)
  - Van Antwerp, William C., 1913 (Folder 15: 24)
  - Vanderbilt, Ann, 1910-1915 (Folder 15: 25)
  - Wardwell, J. Otis and Mary, 1921-1931 (Folder 15: 26)
  - Warner, H. B. and Mary, 1912-1913 (Folder 15: 27)
  - Washburn, Robert M., 1913-1935 (Folder 16: 1)
  - Weeks, John W., 1912-1921 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Welldon, Samuel Alfred, 1904-1905 (Folder 16: 3)
  - Welsh, Albert F., 1927-1930 (Folder 16: 4)
  - Wendell, Barrett, 1907-1908 (Folder 16: 5)
  - White, Henry, 1910-1922 (Folder 16: 6)
  - White, Horace, 1908-1913 (Folder 16: 7)
  - Whitman, Sarah de St. Croix, 1903 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Whitney, Dorothy, 1910 (Folder 16: 9)
  - Whittemore, Jim, 1898-1901 (Folder 16: 10)
  - Wickersham, George W., 1911-1926 (Folder 16: 11)
  - Wilbur, Curtis D., 1926 (Folder 16: 12)